Evan Hosni

Issaquah WA 98027 evanhosni.com -

- 360-704-0795 - linkedin.com/in/evanhosni

evankhaledhosni@gmail.comgithub.com/evanhosni

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a knack for UI/UX. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Always expanding knowledge by keeping abreast of the evolving trends, techniques, and technologies. Earned a bachelor's degree and bootcamp certificate and built professional experience in multiple industries.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript/jQuery/JSX, HTML, CSS, C#, Ruby (RGSS1)

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL/Sequelize, MongoDB/Mongoose, JSON/API Integration, Web Cl. Web Control (Control of the City of the Handley)

WebGL, WebSockets/SocketIO, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Heroku

Applications: Webflow, Insomnia, MongoDB Compass, Adobe Creative Suite, Cubase, Pro Tools, Albeton,

Unity, Unreal Engine, Wwise (certified), FMOD, Blender

PROJECTS

[dotcomma] - dotcomma.io - gitlab.com/evanhosni/dotcomma

A browser-based MMO video game featuring all original music, 3D design, and animation, as well as an infinite, procedurally-generated terrain. (Still in early development).

Responsibilities: Solo project. Developing game in Unity, utilizing SocketIO for online multiplayer synchronization, and storing user data in a MySQL database. Designing 3D models and composing music.

Languages: C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Unity, WebGL, FMOD, SocketIO, MySQL/Sequelize, Cubase, Blender, Adobe Photoshop

Pocket Rascal - evanhosni.github.io/pocket-rascal - github.com/evanhosni/pocket-rascal

A virtual pet to take care of, play games with, and customize.

Responsibilities: Developed the frontend. Designed UI/UX. Procedurally animated in-app characters. Researched and implemented the Matter.js physics engine and developed plans for future monetization.

Languages: JavaScript/JSX, HTML, CSS

Technologies: React.js, Matter.js, Material UI, MySQL/Sequelize, Adobe Photoshop

Wacky-Wiki - evanhosni.github.io/wackywiki - github.com/evanhosni/wackywiki

A 'Mad Libs' style party game using any Wikipedia article.

Responsibilities: Developed entire frontend. Designed UI/UX. Integrated both MediaWiki and Web Speech

APIs. Animated 'Wacky Wilfred'.

Languages: JavaScript/jQuery, HTML, CSS

Technologies: MediaWiki API, Web Speech API, Bootstrap, Local Storage

MetaMemeMarket - <u>meta-meme-market.herokuapp.com</u> - <u>github.com/evanhosni/meta-meme-market</u>

A stock market for memes.

Responsibilities: Planned and designed UX. Integrated Cloudinary image hosting service, as well as signup, login, logout, and upload image functionalities.

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Express.js, Handlebars, MySQL/Sequelize, Cloudinary

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Education Services – New York NY

March 2022 - Present

Instructional Specialist for University of Washington Coding Boot Camp (Remote)

- Aiding 40+ students with web dev curriculum and leading class through practice activities
- Recommended by my boot camp instructor for the role of T.A. after being recognized for my technical abilities, leadership skills, clear communication, and desire to help my peers succeed

Evan is an innovative developer with an infectious can-do attitude, making him the ideal mentor - Joe Rehfuss, Instructor

AlphaBEST Education – Winston-Salem NC

January 2022 - Present

Web Developer (Remote)

- Developing an employee-facing intranet to facilitate communication and efficiency
- Collaborating with graphic designers to bring their vision to life via clean, responsive UI and UX
- Utilizing Webflow framework and Memberstack API as well as custom backend script to automate account creation and deletion via data from Google Sheets database

Evan is a great listener and always adds an element of fun - Brian, Chief Technology Officer

Evan Hosni Audio – Issaquah WA

December 2020 - Present

Sound Designer, Music Composer, Foley Artist, Audio Producer (Contract)

DMAC Studios / Ultimate Invasion - Palm Beach FL

- Achieved IMDb credit as Sound Designer and Composer for all 8 episodes of Amazon Prime Video series, Ultimate Invasion
- Collaborated with Director Greg LeSar on the creative direction of the show's audio and met timesensitive deadlines

Green Mouse Academy – Palm Beach FL

- Produced audio for 200+ children's educational videos to date
- Collaborated with a team of editors to complete projects on time and developed strategies to streamline workflow

Evan masters the art of storytelling through audio. He was born to do this – Greg LeSar, Director/Writer – Ultimate Invasion Evan, you are a talented professional and an absolute pleasure to work with – Shane VanderKooi, CEO – Green Mouse Academy

Guitar Center – Tukwila WA, Redmond WA

July 2015 - March 2021

Repair Technician – 2015 - 2019

Area Specialist - 2019 - 2021

- Cultivated a dedicated customer following by focusing on the customer experience
- Recognized by D'Addario Musical Instruments as a top performer in 2017
- Developed promotional programs to engage repair techs in incremental selling activities

Evan is a god among repair techs and an overall cool guy - Owen, Customer

EDUCATION

University of Washington Coding Boot Camp – Certificate of Completion August 2021 – December 2021 300+ hour course on dynamic full stack coding curriculum

Awarded Best UI/UX for all three student projects as well as People's Choice for 'Wacky-Wiki'

Berklee College of Music – Bachelor of Professional Studies

June 2016 - December 2020

Interdisciplinary Music Studies – Focus in Sound Design (Dean's List – six consecutive quarters)

Evan, another awesome soundscape! Man, I love hearing what you put together...really excited about this - Will Robertson, Professor

January 2000 Brasser